<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Dawn of Man -->
<Civ4GameText>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DAWN_OF_MAN_SCREEN_TITLE</Tag>
		<English>DAWN OF A CIVILIZATION</English>
		<French>DAWN OF A CIVILIZATION</French>
		<German>DAWN OF A CIVILIZATION</German>
		<Italian>DAWN OF A CIVILIZATION</Italian>
		<Spanish>DAWN OF A CIVILIZATION</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_AMERICA</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1776 AD. Discontent with foreign domination, the people in the American colonies have risen up in revolution to found their own nation. However, their fledgling republic is still in danger of being reclaimed by European colonial powers and has to surpass its former masters to fulfill its manifest destiny.</English>
		<French>No Translation</French>
		<German>No Translation</German>
		<Italian>No Translation</Italian>
		<Spanish>No Translation</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_CANADA</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1867. After the American revolution, Canada has remained under colonial control. With the approval of the North America Acts, Canada has now been finally granted independence so it can expand across the Great White North on its own accord.</English>
		<French>No Translation</French>
		<German>No Translation</German>
		<Italian>No Translation</Italian>
		<Spanish>No Translation</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_CONNECTICUT</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1635 AD. Puritan settlers from the Bay Colony led by Reverend Thomas Hooker venture South to look for land for their free government. Encroaching on Dutch trading grounds, the new colony must gather its defense and bolster itself against its larger neighbors in order to persevere.</English>
		<French>No Translation</French>
		<German>No Translation</German>
		<Italian>No Translation</Italian>
		<Spanish>No Translation</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_DELAWARE</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1682 AD. The Delaware River has long been the site of Swedish and Dutch fur trading outposts, but with the conquest of New Amsterdam, Dutch holdings passed to the English. Administered by Maryland, and then Pennsylvania, the time has come for the people of Delaware to for their own government.</English>
		<French>No Translation</French>
		<German>No Translation</German>
		<Italian>No Translation</Italian>
		<Spanish>No Translation</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_ENGLAND</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1600 AD. The Spanish and the Portuguese Empires have claimed and exploited vast tracts of land across the New World, gaining riches and power beyond imagine. As the plans for another British expedition to succeed the Roanoke Colony emerge, the British nobility looks North of New Spain to for their empire.</English>
		<French>No Translation</French>
		<German>No Translation</German>
		<Italian>No Translation</Italian>
		<Spanish>No Translation</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_FRANCE</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1600 AD. French explorers are no stranger to the New World, having plotted routes across the continent. The promise of trade with natives encourages the funding of establishing trading posts and even alliances with the locals to protect French claims.</English>
		<French>No Translation</French>
		<German>No Translation</German>
		<Italian>No Translation</Italian>
		<Spanish>No Translation</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_GEORGIA</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1732 AD. The British Colonies have grown powerful and populous, and look for room to expand; however, a centuries old rival in Spain threatens the profitable plantations of Carolina. General James Oglethrope secures a charter to found the Province of Georgia to buffer the Colonies from New Spain, but he dreams of building a haven for free men.</English>
		<French>No Translation</French>
		<German>No Translation</German>
		<Italian>No Translation</Italian>
		<Spanish>No Translation</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_MARYLAND</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1634 AD. Catholic Lord Baltimore inherited a colonial charter from his late father for a fertile land encircling the Chesapeake Bay. Flanked in the South by Protestant Virginia, in East by the Swedes, and the West by increasingly suspicious natives, forging a new unique identity in the British New World might require more alliances than guns.</English>
		<French>No Translation</French>
		<German>No Translation</German>
		<Italian>No Translation</Italian>
		<Spanish>No Translation</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_MASSACHUSETTS</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1620 AD. Persecuted Pilgrims set sail to find freedom in a wild unknown. With great hardships ahead, a strong sense of community will be needed to form a tradition of accepting religious immigrants, shaping an influential culture in an emerging nation.</English>
		<French>No Translation</French>
		<German>No Translation</German>
		<Italian>No Translation</Italian>
		<Spanish>No Translation</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_NETHERLANDS</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1600 AD. Dutch independence sparks a golden age of thought and art in the Low Countries and finances a growing merchant fleet. Following success in the West Indies, a new trading company seeks to dominate profitable fur routes in the New World.</English>
		<French>No Translation</French>
		<German>No Translation</German>
		<Italian>No Translation</Italian>
		<Spanish>No Translation</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_NEW_HAMPSHIRE</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1623 AD. A group of English fishermen make landfall and start the early settlements of the Upper Plantation, but more immigrants are soon to arrive from Europe and the Bay Colony to the South. Disorganization among the settlers is will be an existential threat, and great acts will be required to prevent becoming subservient to the more powerful Massachusetts.</English>
		<French>No Translation</French>
		<German>No Translation</German>
		<Italian>No Translation</Italian>
		<Spanish>No Translation</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_NEW_JERSEY</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1664 AD. With the fall of the New Netherlands, large tracts of land become available for British rule. Formerly New Sweden, the land East of the Delaware river promises bountiful harvest, but can its people hold their own against the successors to the crown jewel of the Dutch, New York?</English>
		<French>No Translation</French>
		<German>No Translation</German>
		<Italian>No Translation</Italian>
		<Spanish>No Translation</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_NEW_YORK</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1664 AD. With the Dutch colonial government conquered, British occupiers set up a government to rule from the newly named New York. While strategically positioned, the colony lacks any buffer around its capital and will need to leverage New York City’s location in order to colonize the vast upstate heartland.</English>
		<French>No Translation</French>
		<German>No Translation</German>
		<Italian>No Translation</Italian>
		<Spanish>No Translation</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_NORTH_CAROLINA</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1653 AD. For over half a century, British settlers avoided Carolina and the ruins of the Roanoke colony; but now settlers from Virginia flock to the borderlands to stake a claim in fertile ground. With rich soil for plantations, North Carolina will need to innovate to set itself apart from its Northern neighbor and its Southern counterpart.</English>
		<French>No Translation</French>
		<German>No Translation</German>
		<Italian>No Translation</Italian>
		<Spanish>No Translation</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_PENNSYLVANIA</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1682 AD. In order to pay a debt, the King grants land West of the Delaware River, obtained through the conquest of New Netherlands, to William Penn. Seeking to create a haven of religious freedom for the Quakers, but the colony’s freedom will entice many other immigrants to bolster Pennsylvania and make it a link between the North and South.</English>
		<French>No Translation</French>
		<German>No Translation</German>
		<Italian>No Translation</Italian>
		<Spanish>No Translation</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_RHODE_ISLAND</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1636 AD. Insert inspiring introduction to Rhode Island.</English>
		<French>No Translation</French>
		<German>No Translation</German>
		<Italian>No Translation</Italian>
		<Spanish>No Translation</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_SOUTH_CAROLINA</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1663 AD. Insert inspiring introduction to South Carolina.</English>
		<French>No Translation</French>
		<German>No Translation</German>
		<Italian>No Translation</Italian>
		<Spanish>No Translation</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_SPAIN</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1600 AD. In the New World, Spain has profited from 100 years of conquest and pillage and built an empire that is the envy of the world. When upstart colonists start crossing the sea to bolster rival nations, Spain will feel the crushing pressure to hold together colonies that stretch across half the globe.</English>
		<French>No Translation</French>
		<German>No Translation</German>
		<Italian>No Translation</Italian>
		<Spanish>No Translation</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_SWEDEN</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1600 AD. Insert inspiring introduction to Sweden.</English>
		<French>No Translation</French>
		<German>No Translation</German>
		<Italian>No Translation</Italian>
		<Spanish>No Translation</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_VIRGINIA</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1607 AD. In a response to Spanish and Portuguese colonization of the New World, King James I charters the Virginia Company to found a permanent presence in virgin land. With colonists in search of gold, easy riches, and glory, Virginia is poised with fertile land to grow a population to greatly influence a fledgling new identity.</English>
		<French>No Translation</French>
		<German>No Translation</German>
		<Italian>No Translation</Italian>
		<Spanish>No Translation</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
