<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Dawn of Man -->
<Civ4GameText>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DAWN_OF_MAN_SCREEN_TITLE</Tag>
		<English>DAWN OF A CIVILIZATION</English>
		<French>DAWN OF A CIVILIZATION</French>
		<German>DAWN OF A CIVILIZATION</German>
		<Italian>DAWN OF A CIVILIZATION</Italian>
		<Spanish>DAWN OF A CIVILIZATION</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_MAYA</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 250 AD. Urbanization on the peninsula of Yucatan sparks the formation of the Mayan city states, whose technological and architectural advancements would create the first advanced civilization in the Americas.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_TEOTIHUACAN</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 250 AD. While the Valley of Mexico has been inhabited for thousands of years, advanced civilization thus far has only flourished East, in the Olmec, Zapotec, and Maya heartlands. Now urban centers are developing around Lake Texcoco. The most prominent is Teotihuacan, poised to influence the culture of all Mesoamerica.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_TIWANAKU</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 250 AD. As the invention of ceramics strengthens existing trade routes, the pilgrimage site of Tiwanaku begins growing into a true city and the first great regional power since the fall of the Norte Chico Civilization. With an economy built on the seasonal swelling of visitors from far and wide, the city of Tiwanaku is primed to grow into an empire of great fame and glory.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_WARI</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 500 AD. North of the flourishing Tiwanaku, the Ayacucho basin harbors the beginning of the Wari Empire. Sharing cultural roots to their neighbors, the Wari innovate new city building techniques in their mountain heartland. As expansion is constrained by seas and ridges, the rise of the Wari heralds what will soon become the first major Andean power struggle.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_MISSISSIPPI</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 600 AD. Cultivation of the “Three Sisters,” maize, beans, and squash, spreads quickly across the wooded valleys of the Ohio River. An agricultural revolution is on the brink in Fort Ancient among its mound-building people. Poised to spread their ideas, culture, and trade across the largest watershed in North America, the Mississippian culture is on the rise.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_PUEBLOAN</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 750 AD. The Hohokam people of the arid foothills have become adept at water conservation, their well-engineered canals irrigating the parched soil. However, due to increasing raids on their bountiful society, the Puebloan make a tactical retreat to the mountains, buildinging their unique cliff-dwellings. But how long can they last against the attackers?</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_MUISCA</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 800 AD. A group of tribes, united by language, come together to form the Muisca Confederation in the high Andes. Plentiful gems and gold promise riches to the loose union of states, so long as they can form a trade network to the empires of the South.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_NORSE</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 874 AD. The scarcity of food makes the inhabitants of Scandinavia excellent sailors that rely on fishing and trade. Their home kingdoms still can't sustain further population growth, and the Vikings have to turn to lands across the sea.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_CHIMU</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 900 AD. Legend states that upon the arrival of Taycanamo in the Moche Valley on a balsa raft, a great dynasty was formed. That dynasty is destined to form an upstart empire, but will surely butt heads with other great powers.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_INUIT</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1050 AD. The Inuit's arrival to the Bering Strait marks the beginning of what will become one of the longest lasting cultures of the arctic.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_INCA</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1100 AD. Manco Capac has just founded the Kingdom of Cuzco, the first Incan kingdom. Even in the harsh environment of the Andes and lacking suitable pack animals, they set out to create an empire never seen before in the Americas.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_AZTECS</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1250 AD. The Aztec peoples have founded the city of Tenochtitlan at Lake Texcoco in the Valley of Mexico. Through clever use of irrigation systems, Tenochtitlan can become the largest metropolis of Mesoamerica and dominate the surrounding cities.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_IROQUOIS</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1450 AD. The Great Peacemaker unites the once bitter enemies of the lake into the Great League of Peace. The five nations draw upon each other for strength, but their might will soon be tested by invaders from far away.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_SPAIN</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1496 AD. After unifying Spain, the Crown hears the proposal of a Genoan explorer to set sail on a new route to Asia. Envious of the newfound riches of the Portuguese, the Spanish monarchs gamble on an unlikely voyage to find riches.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_SPAIN_1500AD</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1500 AD. The discovery of tropical islands across the Atlantic sends waves throughout European countries hopeful for resources and power. Spain finds itself on the forefront of the colonial rush and is eager to press her early advantage.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_SPAIN_1750AD</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1750 AD. The Spanish Empire is in a state of decline. Income from the American colonies is diminishing, the cultural flourishing of the last century has come to an end, and now the ruling Habsburg dynasty is about to die out. Seeing weakness, colonial-born statesmen lie in wait for an opportunity to break away.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_PORTUGAL</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1532 AD. The Portuguese Crown laid claim to Brazil three decades prior however gave it little interest due to the profits of its African and Indian endeavors. In a scheme to develop the claimed land without needing to pay for its colonies, the Crown grants hereditary Captaincies to Portuguese noblemen who would build and rule in its stead. Chiefly concerned only for profit, these new Captains are now on the lookout for labor.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_PORTUGAL_1750AD</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1750 AD. In the last century, Portugal has regained its independence from the Spanish crown. Many of its colonial possessions have been lost to the Dutch, but Brazil is still under Portuguese control and promises wealth for the future.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_ENGLAND</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1607 AD. Unfettered by the two failures at Roanoke, the British crown establishes the Virginia Company to restart its claim on the New World. Although starting later than the Spanish and Portuguese, the British have great pools of manpower to draw upon to settle the virgin land.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_ENGLAND_1750AD</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1750 AD. For the past century, the British and French crowns have vied for supremacy over North America. Making a web of alliances with native tribes, the two are poised to start a great conflict over the continent; however, the fallout of which is sure to have consequences among their subjects.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_FRANCE</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1608 AD. After the modest success of the Port Royal colony, the French Crown sponsors Samuel de Champlain to found Quebec City. Smartly allying with local tribes, Champlain starts a legacy of cooperation and trade with the natives, who might eventually follow France into wars with other colonial aggressors.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_FRANCE_1750AD</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1750 AD. War is brewing on the horizon as Britain and France posture over the Ohio River Valley. Although vast in territory, New France distinctly lacks the manpower to defend such great distances. Savvy alliances with the native powers in the region could just turn the tide.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_NETHERLANDS</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1625 AD. The success of the Dutch East India Company spurs the initial funding of one million guilders for a sister company in the West. Deft in trade and even more deft in hijacking it, the Dutch seek to found outposts across the Americas to build their riches.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_NETHERLANDS_1750AD</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1750 AD. Hampered by the English at every turn, Dutch prospects in the New World seem to be drawing to a close. Perhaps an impending war could sow enough discord for a last attempt to seize territory?</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_HAWAII</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1650 AD. Inhabited for hundreds of years by the descendents of bold seafarers, scattered tribes dot the paradisiacal islands. Soon the people of Hawai’i must find common cause, as a different band of seafarers will soon dot the horizon. Whether that common cause is achieved through lu’au or through cannon is yet to be seen.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_HAWAII_1750AD</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1750 AD. Inhabited for hundreds of years by the descendents of bold seafarers, scattered tribes dot the paradisiacal islands. Soon the people of Hawai’i must find common cause, as a different band of seafarers will soon dot the horizon. Whether that common cause is achieved through lu’au or through cannon is yet to be seen.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_RUSSIA</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1743 AD. Having reached the far end of Siberia, Russian frontiersmen cross the Bering Strait for fur trading prospects in the New World. The Promyshlenniki, Sibero-Russian serfs, scour the land for pelts and prisoners whom they can make work hauling and building.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_RUSSIA_1750AD</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1750 AD. Having reached the far end of Siberia, Russian frontiersmen cross the Bering Strait for fur trading prospects in the New World. The Promyshlenniki, Sibero-Russian serfs, scour the land for pelts and prisoners whom they can make work hauling and building.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_AMERICA</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1776 AD. Discontent with foreign domination, the people in the American colonies have risen up in revolution to found their own nation. However, their fledgling republic is still in danger of being reclaimed by European colonial powers and has to surpass its former masters to fulfill its manifest destiny.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_HAITI</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1804 AD. A great and bloody war has raged throughout Hispanola for over a decade. Finally reigning victorious, the once slaves now decide the fate of their new nation. With odds steeped against them by racist foreign adversaries, will the Haitians crumble under the weight of their new republic, or see the light of emancipation through to the millions of others in bondage?</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_ARGENTINA</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1810 AD. Spurred by the weakness of the Spanish Empire and the ideals of the French Revolution, the people in the Viceroyalty of the Rio de la Plata have overthrown their viceroy and started a revolution to form the Argentine Republic.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_MEXICO</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1810 AD. Political instability and warfare in the European motherland have strengthened calls for independence in New Spain. Now that even former loyalists have joined the republican cause, the Mexican Republic has established itself.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_COLOMBIA</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1814 AD. War in Europe weakened their grip on Latin America, and new ideas of nationalism and democracy raised calls for self-determination in New Granada. With the victories of Sim&#243;n Bol&#237;var in Venezuela, the way has been paved for Colombian independence.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_PERU</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1822 AD. A joint effort of the forces of Sim&#243;n Bol&#237;var and Jos&#233; de San Mart&#237;n liberates Peru from Royalist forces. The two leaders meet at the Guyaquil Conference to decide the fate of the new nation. Bol&#237;var advocates for a republic, while San Mart&#237;n calls for a constitutional monarchy. As both men are drawn away to their own conflicts, Peru must decide its future for itself.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_BRAZIL</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1822 AD. After the revolution in Portugal threatens Brazilian sovereignty within the United Kingdom, Dom Pedro of Brazil declares an independent empire. Brazil's rich plantations as well as the Amazon rainforest promise wealth for the future, but also demand preservation.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_VENEZUELA</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1831 AD. Sim&#243;n Bol&#237;var’s vision of Gran Colombia is disintegrating around him. Unrest in Peru and Venezuela provinces strain his attention as opportunists seek to slip away under their own new governments. Can this break-away stand on its own against the ire of Bol&#237;var?</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_CANADA</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1867. After the American revolution, Canada has remained under colonial control. With the approval of the North America Acts, Canada has now been finally granted independence so it can expand across the Great White North on its own accord.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_CUBA</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1898 AD. Staying royalist throughout the revolutionary period of Latin America, Cubans grew ever more discontent at their oppressive Spanish rule. Sympathetic to their plight, the United States steps in with dubious justification to liberate the island. After a small transitionary period, Cubans will get the opportunity to live in a republic of their own making. But was the almost unilaterally American drafted Cuban government not entirely in good faith?</English>
	</TEXT>
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
</Civ4GameText>
